Finding Aid for Paul L. Adams Papers, 1924-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Paul L. Adams papers 1924-1976
Adams, Paul L. (Paul Lincoln), 1908-
4 linear feet
85778 Aa 2
Attorney, regent of the University of Michigan; state attorney general; justice on the Michigan Supreme Court. Correspondence with Adams' family concerning his activities as a student at University of Michigan and as Supreme Court justice; also topical files, speeches, and miscellaneous legal records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Paul L. Adams (donor no. 5415 ) and came to the library in August 1973.
The collection is open to research.
Paul L. Adams was born April 9, 1908 in Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan. He received his BA degree from the University of Michigan in 1930, his MA in 1931, and his LL.B in 1936. He practiced law in Sault Ste. Marie except for 1943-1944 when he served with the Board of Economic Warfare in Washington DC. In addition to his law practice, Adams was mayor of Sault Ste. Marie, 1938-1942; chair of the Sault Ste. Marie Charter Commission, 1950; member of the Michigan Social Welfare Commission, 1949; and regent of the University of Michigan, 1956-1957. In 1958, he was appointed by Governor William to fill out a term as state attorney general, then was elected in his own right in 1958 and 1960. In December 1961, he was appointed the Michigan Supreme Court, then elected in 1962. He served on the court until 1972, then was appointed to the Michigan Court of Appeals in 1973. He died November 23, 1990.
The papers of Paul Adams concentrate on his years as a student at the University of Michigan,1926-1936,and on his years as a Michigan Supreme Court Justice, January 2,1962-January 1,1973. These papers include detailed letters to his family and topical files on his various interests and affairs. The correspondence file contains letters from former Governor Williams, Senator Philip A. Hart, Mrs. Chase Osborn, and other leading Michigan figures and politicians. His speech file includes topics on law, crime, politics, and religion.
Subjects:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Judges--Michigan.; Michigan. Dept. of Attorney General.; Michigan. Supreme Court.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.
Contributors:
Joiner, Charles Wycliffe, 1916-; Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.
- Michigan Supreme Court
  - Memoranda concerning his career on the Michigan Supreme Court 1976 (Box 1)
- Family correspondence
  - 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971 (Box 1)
  - 1972 (Box 1)
- Student records
  - 1926-1930 (Box 1)
- Topical File 1958-1973
  - Atlantic Council (Box 2)
  - Camp Lucas (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Conferences (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Eastern Upper Peninsula Bar Association (Box 2)
  - Ecumenical Association (Box 2)
  - Episcopal Society for Cultural and Racial Unity (Box 2)
  - Farmers Club (Box 2)
  - Income tax 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Irish (Box 2)
  - Joiner, Charles (Box 2)
  - McCarthy for President (Box 2)
  - Monocle Lake (Box 2)
  - Michigan Welfare League (Box 2)
  - NAACP (Box 2)
  - National Lawyers Guild (Box 2)
  - Nut Growers (Box 2)
  - Osborn, Mrs. Chase (Box 2)
  - Planned Parenthood (Box 2)
  - Polish (Box 2)
  - Political File (Box 2)
  - St. Katharine Church (Box 3)
  - Soo Gas Company (Box 3)
  - Soo Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Speeches (Box 3)
  - Harry S. Truman Library (Box 3)
  - Union Carbide Company (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan Alumni Club. (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan Law Review (Box 3)
  - Upper Peninsula Club (Box 3)
  - Upper Peninsula Craftsman (Box 3)
  - Williams, G. Mennen (Box 3)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 3)
- Other papers
  - Legal and real estate memoranda (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous family correspondence and postcard (unsorted) (Box 4)
  - Printed miscellanea (Box 4)